<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>UW on Juiceright</title>
    <link>https://cywd123.github.io/tags/uw/</link>
    <description>Recent content in UW on Juiceright</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.152.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 10:20:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://cywd123.github.io/tags/uw/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>992</title>
      <link>https://cywd123.github.io/posts/%E5%8C%BB%E5%AD%A6%E9%A2%98%E7%9B%AE/uw/992/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 18:08:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cywd123.github.io/posts/%E5%8C%BB%E5%AD%A6%E9%A2%98%E7%9B%AE/uw/992/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;内分泌学笔记家族性低尿钙性高钙血症fhh与钙敏感受体&#34;&gt;内分泌学笔记：家族性低尿钙性高钙血症（FHH）与钙敏感受体&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;题目原文英文&#34;&gt;题目原文（英文）&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 14-year-old boy is brought to the emergency department after accidental ingestion of a chicken bone that lodged in his esophagus（食管）. Upper endoscopy is performed and the bone is successfully removed. However, the patient is incidentally found to have mild hypercalcemia（高钙血症） on laboratory testing. On follow-up with his primary care provider 2 weeks later, he has no symptoms and clinical examination is unremarkable. Further questioning reveals that several of his family members also have mild hypercalcemia. Subsequent laboratory studies show a borderline high parathyroid hormone（甲状旁腺激素） concentration, very low urinary calcium level, and normal 25-hydroxyvitamin D level. A mutation in which of the following receptors is most likely responsible for this patient’s laboratory abnormalities?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>995</title>
      <link>https://cywd123.github.io/posts/%E5%8C%BB%E5%AD%A6%E9%A2%98%E7%9B%AE/uw/995/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 18:08:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cywd123.github.io/posts/%E5%8C%BB%E5%AD%A6%E9%A2%98%E7%9B%AE/uw/995/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;磷脂酰肌醇第二信使系统知识点笔记&#34;&gt;磷脂酰肌醇第二信使系统知识点笔记&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;英文原版题目&#34;&gt;英文原版题目&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A research scientist develops an agent that specifically blocks the interaction of inositol triphosphate（肌醇三磷酸，IP₃）with its intracellular receptor. A study is then performed in which vascular smooth muscle cells are divided into 2 groups: an experimental group treated with the receptor blocker and an untreated control group. Both groups are exposed to phenylephrine（去氧肾上腺素）. Compared to the control cells, decreased activity of which of the following enzymes is most likely to be observed in the experimental cells?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>996</title>
      <link>https://cywd123.github.io/posts/%E5%8C%BB%E5%AD%A6%E9%A2%98%E7%9B%AE/uw/996/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 18:08:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cywd123.github.io/posts/%E5%8C%BB%E5%AD%A6%E9%A2%98%E7%9B%AE/uw/996/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;代谢性酸中毒与酶活性变化---笔记&#34;&gt;代谢性酸中毒与酶活性变化 - 笔记&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;英文原版题目&#34;&gt;英文原版题目&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 64-year-old man comes to the emergency department due to severe abdominal pain, nausea, and vomiting.&lt;br&gt;
Medical history is significant for hypertension, myocardial infarction, and heart failure with reduced ejection fraction（射血分数降低）. The patient does not use alcohol but smokes a half-pack of cigarettes daily. Temperature is 37.6 C (99.7 F), blood pressure is 100/60 mm Hg, pulse is 116/min and irregular, and respirations are 24/min. The abdomen is soft, mildly distended, and mildly tender without rebound or guarding. Laboratory results are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>989</title>
      <link>https://cywd123.github.io/posts/%E5%8C%BB%E5%AD%A6%E9%A2%98%E7%9B%AE/uw/989/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 18:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cywd123.github.io/posts/%E5%8C%BB%E5%AD%A6%E9%A2%98%E7%9B%AE/uw/989/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;知识点笔记着色性干皮病xeroderma-pigmentosum&#34;&gt;知识点笔记：着色性干皮病（Xeroderma Pigmentosum）&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;题目英文原版&#34;&gt;题目（英文原版）&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 5-year-old girl is brought to the office by her mother because she is concerned that her daughter &amp;ldquo;sunburns too easily.&amp;rdquo; The mother says the patient&amp;rsquo;s skin becomes red and scaly with only minimal sun exposure. She first noticed the problem when her daughter was 7 months old during a trip to the beach. The mother has since avoided exposing her child to excess sunlight, but finds it difficult now that the patient has begun kindergarten. Physical examination shows thin and hyperpigmented（色素沉着过度的） skin. She also has a few nevi（痣） on her hands that have been enlarging rapidly. This patient&amp;rsquo;s disorder is most likely due to a primary defect involving which of the following processes?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>788</title>
      <link>https://cywd123.github.io/posts/%E5%8C%BB%E5%AD%A6%E9%A2%98%E7%9B%AE/uw/788/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 18:08:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cywd123.github.io/posts/%E5%8C%BB%E5%AD%A6%E9%A2%98%E7%9B%AE/uw/788/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;高同型半胱氨酸血症与mthfr缺陷的代谢机制笔记&#34;&gt;高同型半胱氨酸血症与MTHFR缺陷的代谢机制笔记&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;题目原文original-question&#34;&gt;题目原文（Original Question）&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 34-year-old previously healthy man comes to the emergency department due to a 3-hour history of chest pain, diaphoresis（出汗）, and dyspnea（呼吸困难）. He does not smoke, exercises regularly, and eats a balanced diet. His father died at age 56 from a myocardial infarction（心肌梗死）. His blood pressure is 110/70 mm Hg and pulse is 110/min and regular.&lt;br&gt;
Physical examination is unremarkable. ECG shows ST elevation in the anterolateral leads. Coronary angiogram reveals proximal left anterior descending artery stenosis and thrombosis（血栓形成）, which is treated with angioplasty and stent placement. Laboratory results are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>757</title>
      <link>https://cywd123.github.io/posts/%E5%8C%BB%E5%AD%A6%E9%A2%98%E7%9B%AE/uw/757/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 18:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cywd123.github.io/posts/%E5%8C%BB%E5%AD%A6%E9%A2%98%E7%9B%AE/uw/757/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;细胞生物学笔记内质网核糖体与蛋白质合成&#34;&gt;细胞生物学笔记：内质网核糖体与蛋白质合成&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;英文原版题目&#34;&gt;英文原版题目&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biologists investigating the morphologic changes associated with reversible cellular injury perform a procedure on anesthetized mice to assess the effects of transient hepatic ischemia（肝脏缺血）. During the experiment, they clamp the hepatic artery and obtain liver biopsy samples at varying intervals. The samples are then examined by electron microscopy. Cells that are exposed to longer ischemic periods are found to have reduced numbers of ribosomes attached to the endoplasmic reticulum. This structural change is most likely to impair which of the following cellular functions?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>790</title>
      <link>https://cywd123.github.io/posts/%E5%8C%BB%E5%AD%A6%E9%A2%98%E7%9B%AE/uw/790/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 18:08:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cywd123.github.io/posts/%E5%8C%BB%E5%AD%A6%E9%A2%98%E7%9B%AE/uw/790/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ras蛋白与ras-mapk信号通路笔记&#34;&gt;Ras蛋白与Ras-MAPK信号通路笔记&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;题目原文英文原版&#34;&gt;题目原文（英文原版）&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 54-year-old woman is evaluated for progressive constipation, anorexia, and a 5.4-kg (12-lb) weight loss over the past several months. Physical examination is unremarkable. Stool guaiac test is positive, and a colonoscopy is performed. An exophytic mass is identified in the sigmoid colon. The patient undergoes a left hemicolectomy, and histopathology of the surgical specimen is positive for adenocarcinoma. Molecular testing of the cancer cells reveals a mutation in the &lt;em&gt;KRAS&lt;/em&gt; gene that results in constitutive activation（组成性激活） of the Ras protein. Under normal circumstances, this protein is only active when bound to which of the following substances?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>701</title>
      <link>https://cywd123.github.io/posts/%E5%8C%BB%E5%AD%A6%E9%A2%98%E7%9B%AE/uw/701/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 18:08:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cywd123.github.io/posts/%E5%8C%BB%E5%AD%A6%E9%A2%98%E7%9B%AE/uw/701/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;软骨发育不全achondroplasia遗传概率笔记&#34;&gt;软骨发育不全（Achondroplasia）遗传概率笔记&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;题目original-question&#34;&gt;题目（Original Question）&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A married couple comes to the office for routine prenatal counseling. The husband is 120 cm (3 ft 11 in) tall with &lt;strong&gt;disproportionately&lt;/strong&gt;（不成比例地） short upper and lower extremities, a large head, and a prominent forehead. He cannot provide a biological family history because he was adopted. His spouse is average height with no &lt;strong&gt;dysmorphic&lt;/strong&gt;（畸形的） features, and her family history is insignificant. They inquire about the likelihood that their offspring will have short stature due to the same condition as the father. Which of the following is the best response to their concerns?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>633</title>
      <link>https://cywd123.github.io/posts/%E5%8C%BB%E5%AD%A6%E9%A2%98%E7%9B%AE/uw/633/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 18:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cywd123.github.io/posts/%E5%8C%BB%E5%AD%A6%E9%A2%98%E7%9B%AE/uw/633/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;亨廷顿病huntington-disease-hd遗传现象-anticipation遗传早现&#34;&gt;亨廷顿病（Huntington Disease, HD）遗传现象—— anticipation（遗传早现）&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;题目原文&#34;&gt;题目原文&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 28-year-old man is evaluated for &lt;strong&gt;abnormal movements&lt;/strong&gt;（异常运动） of the hands and face. The patient reports that he started experiencing &lt;strong&gt;involuntary grimacing&lt;/strong&gt;（不自主做鬼脸） a year ago, which has gradually worsened. He is taking a selective serotonin reuptake inhibitor for &lt;strong&gt;major depression&lt;/strong&gt;（重度抑郁症） but has not taken any antipsychotic medications. His 52-year-old father was diagnosed with an &lt;strong&gt;inherited movement disorder&lt;/strong&gt;（遗传性运动障碍） 2 months ago. Physical examination shows normal strength and normal deep tendon reflexes. No sensory deficits are noted. Which of the following best explains the difference in disease presentation between this patient and his father?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>596</title>
      <link>https://cywd123.github.io/posts/%E5%8C%BB%E5%AD%A6%E9%A2%98%E7%9B%AE/uw/596/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 18:07:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cywd123.github.io/posts/%E5%8C%BB%E5%AD%A6%E9%A2%98%E7%9B%AE/uw/596/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;线粒体遗传疾病与异质性heteroplasmy知识点笔记&#34;&gt;线粒体遗传疾病与异质性（Heteroplasmy）知识点笔记&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;题目原文含难点词汇翻译&#34;&gt;题目原文（含难点词汇翻译）&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 12-year-old boy is brought to the clinic for evaluation of muscle weakness. The patient has a history of seizures（癫痫）, and he has recently had several stroke-like episodes（类卒中发作） that resulted in muscle weakness. Examination shows decreased strength in the upper and lower extremities on the left compared to the right. Laboratory evaluation shows increased serum lactate levels both after exercise and at rest. Further work-up confirms that the patient has a genetic condition that is transmitted exclusively through the maternal line（母系遗传）. His older sister is affected by the same disorder, but she displays very few symptoms. Which of the following is the most likely explanation for the variability in clinical presentation between this patient and his sister?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
